

## About me

I am a Mechanical Engineer with a master in economics and public policy. In 2021, I was enrolled in a top 5 European Ph.D. in Economics but decided to transition into Data Science/ML.

I grew up in Rio de Janeiro and education was the only weapon I had to succeed in life. As a consequence, I was awarded by Yale University, UCLA, General Electric Foundation, Lemann Foundation, and The Club of Rome.

What differentiates me from others in DS/ML is that I bring to the table a solid knowledge of how econometrics & causal inference can substantiate new insights as well as some experience in both FinTech (payments) and consulting in the Education sector.

## Education

### PhD in Economics (Unfinished), Tilburg University

SEPTEMBER 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2021

Awarded the Koopmans Scholarship for academic excellence.

## Master of Economics & Public Policy, University of California Los Angeles

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2019

Awarded the Lemann Foundation Fellowship, which is given to top Brazilians who are accepted at UCLA, Harvard, Stanford, MIT, Columbia, and Oxford.

## BSc in Mechanical Engineering, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (UFRJ)

AUGUST 2007 - DECEMBER 2012

Top 1% student among 100 students. UFRJ is a top 3 Latin American University.

# Work Experience

### Pre-Doctoral Research Assistant, Royal Holloway, University of London

NOVEMBER 2019 - APRIL 2020

Worked independently and used STATA programming code to perform statistical and econometrics (causal analysis) for large datasets from a World Bank project on the relationship between climate change and agriculture productivity.

### Research & Teaching Assistant, University of California Los Angeles (UCLA)

OCTOBER 2018 - JUNE 2019

Worked independently and used STATA programming code to perform statistical and econometrics (causal analysis) for large datasets on a research project on the relationship between family planning and access to welfare.

#### Founder, MePrepara.com.br

JUNE 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2017

MePrepara is an automated online course to prepare Brazilian students for GRE and GMAT (exams required by the most prestigious MBA, MSc, and Ph.D programs in the world). Developed 140 math videos and over 300 exercises with solutions. Designed the Digital Marketing strategy (Blogging, SEO, Email Marketing). Developed partnerships with Brazilian and American institutions.

### **Details**

+31 613661021 caiocvelasco@gmail.com

## Social & Projects

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

### Skills

Math, Statistics, Economics, Econometrics (PhD-Level)

Causal Inference, Experimentation

Python, STATA

R

SQL

#### HTML/CSS

In training: NumPy, Pandas, Seaborn, Spicy, Scikit-learn, Keras, TensorFlow

Microsoft Office

Project & Time Management

Leadership and Teamwork

Communication skills

**Business Skills** 

Entrepreneurial skills

Banking & Finance

**Empathy** 

Service to the Community

## Languages

**English** 

Portuguese

#### Consultant, AOG Education Consulting, São Paulo, Brazil

JANUARY 2015 - DECEMBER 2015

Worked independently and reported directly to the founder and to the schools' director. Examined two large private schools' operations (3000 students) in two different states in Brazil. Traveled weekly across the country. Mapped processes on the staffing structure, budget preparation, enrollment procedures, and the school education system. Identified new sources of revenue based on new enrollment procedures. Developed a plan of action for improvements following proprietary procedures.

### Entrepreneur in Residence, Stone Payments, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

DECEMBER 2012 - DECEMBER 2014

Stone was a Brazilian FinTech startup that grew from a team of 3 employees to over 3000 in less than 5 years. I was one of the 3 employees.

Designed from scratch the first draft of Stone's credit card reconciliation process (authorization, settlement, chargeback, adjustments, and receivables). Reported directly to the founders.

Conducted 1-to-1 meetings with CEOs, CFOs, and commercial bank executives across Brazil and USA. Acquired B2B experience.

Worked with large, cross-functional (e.g.: product, sales, customer success, finance) and cross-regional teams.

## **Awards**

### Yale University - Global Pre-MBA Leadership Program, USA

Top 60 young people all over the world selected to explore MBA education.

## Lemann Foundation Fellowship, Brazil & UCLA

Top young professionals from Brazil with academic excellence who were accepted for a master program at Harvard, Stanford, MIT, Columbia, or UCLA.

#### The Club of Rome, Switzerland

Invited to participate in the Change Course Conference with leading personalities (politicians, CEOs, etc) from all over the world to discuss global issues.

#### General Electric Scholar-Leader

Global scholarship awarded to the top 10 Brazilian engineering students with both leadership and social skills.

#### Top 1% Student, Federal University of Rio de Janeiro (UFRJ)

Awarded the highest recognition due to the highest grade among all mechanical engineering students. UFRJ is a top 3 Latin American University.

## **Hobbies**

Competitive Football (Offensive Midfield), Running, Travelling, Hiking, Volunteering.